<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<title>Some Notes</title>
	<subtitle>sloppy stuff</subtitle>
	
	<link href="https://capybar.github.io/feed/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
	<link href="https://capybar.github.io/blog/"/>
	<updated>2020-05-10T20:00:00-04:00</updated>
	<id>https://capybar.github.io/blog/</id>
	<author>
		<name>Your Name Here</name>
		<email>youremailaddress@example.com</email>
	</author>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Adventure Time</title>
		<link href="https://capybar.github.io/posts/2020-05-03-Adventure-Time/"/>
		<updated>2020-05-02T20:00:00-04:00</updated>
		<id>https://capybar.github.io/posts/2020-05-03-Adventure-Time/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I love Tumblr, I really do but I think I let the ease of producing stop me from moving forward. The community is fun and I still plan to stick around making themes here or there but it&#39;s finally time to branch out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right now I&#39;m currently writing my posts in &lt;a href=&quot;https://typora.io/&quot;&gt;Typora&lt;/a&gt; in mark down  and man it&#39;s bringing me back to the days of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.latex-project.org/&quot;&gt;LaTeX&lt;/a&gt; which is actually pretty funny because this text editor supports &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mathjax.org/&quot;&gt;MathJax&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Writing is actually fun! I know I post nonsense on Twitter and Tumblr but this blog let&#39;s me post learning nonsense in longform. I am excited to press on with learning front end and actually documenting my experience. The best part? I own the data on this here computer and can write OFF LINE!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Setting Up Eleventy</title>
		<link href="https://capybar.github.io/posts/firstpost/"/>
		<updated>2020-05-03T20:00:00-04:00</updated>
		<id>https://capybar.github.io/posts/firstpost/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m an avid user of Tumblr. I love Tumblr. I love the functionality and how quick it is to make a theme. I love the theme developing community BUT I don&#39;t like the writing experience. It&#39;s good for long notes however what if I want to post crap? And I always want to post crap!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My first foray with Static Site Generators was with Jekyll but I found it difficult to set up. Gems? What and why do I need that? Making a theme for Jekyll is kind of a hassle. Also at the time, Jekyll was not easy to use for a Windows person like me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.11ty.dev/&quot;&gt;llty&lt;/a&gt; is very easy and quick to install. Here&#39;s a guide to how I set it up. This is not the best guide or the best way to do things but ya know, we&#39;re all learning and having fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;pre-install&quot;&gt;Pre-install &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;#pre-install&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before doing anything, stop and &lt;a href=&quot;https://learntocodewith.me/getting-started/topics/command-line/&quot;&gt;learn a bit&lt;/a&gt; about the command line. &lt;a href=&quot;https://git-scm.com/book/en/v2/Getting-Started-Installing-Git&quot;&gt;Install Git&lt;/a&gt; and watch + work out the git tutorial from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=SWYqp7iY_Tc&quot;&gt;Traversy Media&#39;s Youtube video&lt;/a&gt; . I do everything from Microsoft&#39;s Command Line and I don&#39;t use the git command line. Next you&#39;ll want to install NPM using the command line. Follow the instructions &lt;a href=&quot;https://phoenixnap.com/kb/install-node-js-npm-on-windows&quot;&gt;for Windows&lt;/a&gt; very carefully.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was a noob and didn&#39;t know what global versus local meant. Local means in a specific folder so only that folder can use what you install. Global means in some designated place that every folder has access to. If you&#39;re coming from Tumbrl, also know that directory means folder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;install-time!!&quot;&gt;Install Time!! &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;#install-time!!&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you are ever stuck, stop and look up the terms you don&#39;t understand!&lt;/em&gt; You don&#39;t need to know everything. You just need to know enough. I didn&#39;t know what liquid format was or njk and I&#39;m still not sure about JSON. &lt;a href=&quot;https://shopify.github.io/liquid/basics/introduction/&quot;&gt;Liquid template language&lt;/a&gt; is very similar to Tumblr&#39;s {block} structures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Create a folder named &lt;em&gt;blog&lt;/em&gt; . I made this folder in my documents folder but it doesn&#39;t really matter where you make it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now hover over that folder, hold the cmd button and right click. Click &amp;quot;copy path&amp;quot;. Another easier way to get the location of the folder is by dropping the folder in your internet browser and copying it from there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the command line type cd and right click paste the location of your blog. Now type &lt;code&gt;npm --version&lt;/code&gt; to make sure you have npm 8 or higher. NPM by the way stands for Node Package Manager. If you do feel free to continue on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Install 11ty by typing &lt;code&gt;npm install -g @11ty/eleventy&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/11ty/eleventy-base-blog&quot;&gt;Clone the 11ty base blog&lt;/a&gt; by clicking the &amp;quot;clone or download&amp;quot; button at that link. Cloning basically means to copy. What I actually did was individually copied the files and folders one at a time and put them in the blog folder because I didn&#39;t really know how cloning worked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back to the command line you&#39;re  going to need to install a few plugins by copy pasting and pressing enter for these:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;npm install @11ty/eleventy-plugin-rss
npm install @11ty/eleventy-plugin-syntaxhighlight
npm install @11ty/eleventy-navigation
npm install markdown-it
npm install markdown-it-anchor
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In your blog folder, look for a file named .eleventy.js. Open it in any old text editor and paste this in it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; eleventyConfig.addPassthroughCopy(&#39;css&#39;)
  return {
    passthroughFileCopy: true
  }// rest of .eleventy.js config
};
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now back in the command line, type &lt;code&gt;eleventy --serve&lt;/code&gt; this will serve your website. Go to &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:8080/&quot;&gt;http://localhost:8080/&lt;/a&gt; and you should be able to see your site. If not that means something wrong happened. Maybe the instructions I gave were terrible.  In that case &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.filamentgroup.com/lab/build-a-blog/&quot;&gt;go here&lt;/a&gt;. Wish I&#39;d discovered this post earlier. Oh well.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Complexity is Sometimes the Problem</title>
		<link href="https://capybar.github.io/posts/2020-05-09-Free-Code_Camp/"/>
		<updated>2020-05-08T20:00:00-04:00</updated>
		<id>https://capybar.github.io/posts/2020-05-09-Free-Code_Camp/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A few months ago I decided to give &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.freecodecamp.org/&quot;&gt;FreeCodeCamp&lt;/a&gt; (FCC) a go. As of submitting this post, I&#39;m basically done with the Responsive Webdesign Certificate. I already knew the majority of this stuff way before FCC, however I still got a lot out of this, especially the projects. The most valuable lesson and challenge is that of using only what you need.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Tribute page gets bad rep for not requiring much. I saw this as an opportunity to try to use as much newness that I didn&#39;t know about prior to FCC. You really can create an entire web page with almost no &lt;code&gt;div&lt;/code&gt; tags.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My CSS usually balloons to over 800 lines of code but this page? 64! And a huge part of this was because of the semantic HTML. It was easier to see how inheritance works once the divs weren&#39;t mysteries. I opted against using front end frameworks and the tiny bit of javascript that I knew because the purpose of this and all things is not to race ahead but to make the most of what you&#39;re learning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can view all my FCC projects on &lt;a href=&quot;https://codepen.io/smolcodes&quot;&gt;Codepen&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Making CSS Art</title>
		<link href="https://capybar.github.io/posts/2020-05-22-beginnerguide/"/>
		<updated>2020-05-10T20:00:00-04:00</updated>
		<id>https://capybar.github.io/posts/2020-05-22-beginnerguide/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today I made a very simple picture of coffee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;codepen&quot; data-height=&quot;265&quot; data-theme-id=&quot;light&quot; data-default-tab=&quot;css,result&quot; data-user=&quot;smolcodes&quot; data-slug-hash=&quot;rNOKMwM&quot; style=&quot;height: 265px; box-sizing: border-box; display: flex; align-items: center; justify-content: center; border: 2px solid; margin: 1em 0; padding: 1em;&quot; data-pen-title=&quot;coffee&quot;&gt;
  &lt;span&gt;See the Pen &lt;a href=&quot;https://codepen.io/smolcodes/pen/rNOKMwM&quot;&gt;
  coffee&lt;/a&gt; by smolcodes (&lt;a href=&quot;https://codepen.io/smolcodes&quot;&gt;@smolcodes&lt;/a&gt;)
  on &lt;a href=&quot;https://codepen.io/&quot;&gt;CodePen&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://static.codepen.io/assets/embed/ei.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is my first time trying to draw something with CSS. I read &lt;a href=&quot;https://hacks.mozilla.org/2014/09/single-div-drawings-with-css/&quot;&gt;Lynn&#39;s&lt;/a&gt; tutorial but was still a bit confused until I got up and actually started the drawing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to CSS&#39;s :before and :after, one div is actually three and if you cheat a bit, the body is also a div so you have access to 5 divs!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For my first piece I tried initially for a complicated shaded coffee cup but that got overwhelming so I switched to a more simpler drawing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The key to this drawing was being organized. There are two parts to a coffee cup: the cup and the handle. The top saying coffee was just for the lolz. This is the canvas&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;div id=&amp;quot;cup&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now for the styling. It&#39;s good to first create a skeleton&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;#cup:before {
//the title is here
}
#cup {
//this is the cup&#39;s body
}
#cup:after {
//this is the 
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once everything was organized, I created the outline of the cup and handle. The z-index is in the order of :before, #div and :after. Only having one element meant I had to be creative about making the handle. A simple trick was to use inset box shadows. Box shadows don&#39;t stack. They always start from the same beginning position so to create the illusion, I had two layers, the background color for the handle and black for the inner line of the handle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;body {
  background:aquamarine;
  display:flex;
  justify-content:center;
}
#cup:before {
  display:block;
  content:&amp;quot;Coffe&amp;quot;;
  color:coral;
  font-weight:bold;
  font-size:52px;
}
#cup {
  border: 6px solid black;
  width: 180px;
  height:200px; 
  margin-top:10%;
  border-radius:0% 0% 60% 60%;
}
#cup:after {
  display:block;
  content: &amp;quot;&amp;quot;;
  height:70px;
  width:40px;
  margin-left:180px;
  margin-top:60px;
  border:6px solid black;
  border-top-right-radius:30%;
  border-bottom-right-radius:30%;
  box-shadow:inset -4px 4px aquamarine,
             inset 0px -4px aquamarine,
             inset -10px 8px black,
             inset -2px -10px black;
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final step was to add a bit more styles. I used the same inset box trick again to create the coffee in the cup with a bit of foam on top.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;body {
  background:aquamarine;
  display:flex;
  justify-content:center;
}
#cup:before {
  display:block;
  content:&amp;quot;Coffe&amp;quot;;
  color:coral;
  font-weight:bold;
  font-size:52px;
  margin-top:-58%;
  margin-left:55%;
  padding-top:10px;
  padding-right:10px;
  z-index:-6;
  border-top:8px solid coral;
}
#cup {
  border: 6px solid black;
  width: 180px;
  height:200px; 
  margin-top:10%;
  border-radius:0% 0% 60% 60%;
  box-shadow: inset 0px 8px 0px white,
         inset 0px 26px 0px burlywood,
             inset 0px 44px 0px aquamarine,
    inset 0px 48px 0px black,
    inset 0px 82px 0px coral,
    inset 0px 86px 0px black,
           90px -100px white;
  z-index:10;
}
#cup:after {
  display:block;
  content: &amp;quot;&amp;quot;;
  height:70px;
  width:40px;
  margin-left:180px;
  margin-top:60px;
  border:6px solid black;
  border-top-right-radius:30%;
  border-bottom-right-radius:30%;
  box-shadow:inset -4px 4px aquamarine,
             inset 0px -4px aquamarine,
             inset -10px 8px black,
             inset -2px -10px black;
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;​&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
</feed>