<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<title>Some Notes</title>
	<subtitle>sloppy stuff</subtitle>
	
	<link href="https://capybar.github.io/feed/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
	<link href="https://capybar.github.io/blog/"/>
	<updated>2020-05-14T20:00:00-04:00</updated>
	<id>https://capybar.github.io/blog/</id>
	<author>
		<name>Your Name Here</name>
		<email>youremailaddress@example.com</email>
	</author>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Todo List Saves The Day</title>
		<link href="https://capybar.github.io/posts/2020-04-23-Todo-List/"/>
		<updated>2020-05-02T20:00:00-04:00</updated>
		<id>https://capybar.github.io/posts/2020-04-23-Todo-List/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Week three of the virus and I&#39;ve caved to the todo list. I don&#39;t like using them because there&#39;s a huge stupid part of me that thinks I&#39;m above using them. As if using is proof of my incompetence. The best part of a todo list is how it forces me to stop focusing on things I can&#39;t control and that has worked more wonders than walking, yoga and slowly drinking coffee combined.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From reading and talking to other people, I can see my feelings of guilt  are not unique (God I want this to be over but also how privelaged am I to have catastrophe pay, to live in a decent sized apartment with roommates and cats, to live in a non dense area that gives me permission to take walks, to have internet, books, games?). And also neither is my lack of knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every day, we are learning more and more about this virus. Almost overnight, previous assumptions are proven false. Having an opinion on this seems silly.  It&#39;s best to leave this to the professionals. But like spectators following a sport, it&#39;s hard not to follow the numbers and catch patterns and try to predict what will happen.&lt;br&gt;
[[MORE]]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;summaries-thus-far&quot;&gt;Summaries thus far &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;#summaries-thus-far&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learning on the Internet&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://getflywheel.com/layout/combine-flexbox-and-css-grids-for-layouts-how-to/&quot;&gt;Grid and Flexbox tutorial&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://dev.to/ananyaneogi/create-a-dark-light-mode-switch-with-css-variables-34l8&quot;&gt;Dark Mode Tutorial&lt;/a&gt; well, it&#39;s kind of funny how slow I am to learning variables&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reading on the Internet&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reading other people&#39;s experiences is calming. Also I desperately miss Old School blogging. And I&#39;m glad it is still alive and kicking&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://botanhical.com/&quot;&gt;Anh&#39;s Blog&lt;/a&gt; She inspired me to try to blog more frequently. Even if it&#39;s about nothing. This post is basically nothing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kooslooijesteijn.net/journal-newest-first&quot;&gt;Koos&#39; Covid  Journal&lt;/a&gt; I    find these posts validating especially because his posts start at about the time covid started effecting me (March 14).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://email.aliabdaal.com/&quot;&gt;Ali Abdaal News Letter&lt;/a&gt; I hate subscribing to news letters mainly because I hate looking at my e-mail. Most mail I get is nonsense and so being the inefficent bum that I am, I put news letters I like in a blog post (such as this one).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://tatianamac.com/writing&quot;&gt;Tatiana Mac&#39;s Writing&lt;/a&gt; Her writing style is jam packed with personality. Reminds me of reading Vonnegut. Everything&#39;s been reminding me of him lately.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of which:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reading off the Internet&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finished Breakfast of Champions: Good, short book. He has a welcoming dark way of writing. I wonder if this book brought any meaningful discussion about race. I grew up in upstate New York and I read To Kill a Mockingbird etc but I don&#39;t know how to put it into words, we read books in a way that didn&#39;t make us feel uncomfortable we didn&#39;t really talk about the substance of the books. Vonnegut&#39;s is an interesting read because he is aware but his characters don&#39;t do much and maybe that&#39;s his point?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interesting also is Dwayne Hoover&#39;s conclusion that people are machines. I&#39;ve been bothered for a while about a drive for machine like precision from people. I&#39;m going to put this thought on the back burner until I can better clearly explain what I mean and what I fear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started reading Tin Drum. That&#39;s it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Played&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Journey: it&#39;s a calming puzzle solving game with an incredible sound&lt;br&gt;
track&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Manifold Garden: I didn&#39;t finish. I eventually got bored. The&lt;br&gt;
novelness of a geometric world kind of wears off quickly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Assemble with Care: Also did not finish because Apple&#39;s free trial&lt;br&gt;
ended. I loved Monument Valley so much and that is the only reason I&lt;br&gt;
tried this game.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Reading Quite A Lot</title>
		<link href="https://capybar.github.io/posts/2020-04-30-Reading/"/>
		<updated>2020-05-02T20:00:00-04:00</updated>
		<id>https://capybar.github.io/posts/2020-04-30-Reading/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I miss drinking a good latte and sitting in a library. I can’t stand being in the same place. I also miss work. I miss specifically making drinks. Maybe one day I’ll be in a spot where I do the drink making stuff once a week but the coding/designing stuff most of the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week I started to get into the groove of things. I try to do yoga every day, walk outside everyday.The problem with blogging is it is restrictive by its public nature. Sorry this is disjointed. I&#39;m slowly wanting to pick up Java again. Right when quarantine is almost over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn’t write more java posts because writing tutorials are really difficult. I try to think of these tutorials as notes to past me. But current me reads them and thinks “Why are they so disjointed? So disconnected?”. I’m left more lost than before. So I’m going to start off a bit easier and write very basic HTML and CSS tutorials. &lt;br&gt;
[[MORE]]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reading on the Web&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://capybar.github.io/posts/2020-04-30-Reading/%5Bhttp://jessicahische.is/thinkingthoughts%5D(http://jessicahische.is/thinkingthoughts)&quot;&gt;Jessica Hische&#39;s Blog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://capybar.github.io/posts/2020-04-30-Reading/%5Bhttps://fangya18.com/category/data-science/python/%5D(https://fangya18.com/category/data-science/python/)&quot;&gt;Fang Ya Python Notes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://eyana.me/&quot;&gt;Eyana Mallari&#39;s Blog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://happyturtlethings.net/exercise-against-depression/&quot;&gt;Importance of Excersizing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://undermywhitecoat.com/&quot;&gt;Under My White Coat&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learning on the Web&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.w3schools.com/jquery/default.asp&quot;&gt;JQUery&lt;/a&gt; I know, it&#39;a about time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://dev.to/ananyaneogi/create-a-dark-light-mode-switch-with-css-variables-34l8&quot;&gt;Ananya Neogi Dark Mode Tutorial&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/29720318/remembering-a-users-button-press&quot;&gt;Dark Mode StackOverflow&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://stuffandnonsense.co.uk/blog/redesigning-your-product-and-website-for-dark-mode&quot;&gt;Andy Clark Dark Mode&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://markdotto.com/2018/11/05/css-dark-mode/&quot;&gt;MDO CSS Dark Mode&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.w3schools.com/css/css3_variables.asp&quot;&gt;W3&#39;s Understanding Variables&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.w3.org/TR/low-vision-needs/#introduction&quot;&gt;Guide to the Web for Visually Impaired&lt;/a&gt; This is of particular importance to me because I am legally blind.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Watching&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Evita in Spanish. I rewatched Pan&#39;s Labyrinth and suddenly want to dust off my high school Spanish.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learning Off the Web&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spanish (sort of). This is mainly through listening to Evita in Spanish and that&#39;s it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;French. Picked up Duolingo again and am watching a ton of French book vloggers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Video editing. This is kind of on/off the web. I&#39;m trying out different filming and sounds with a Google Pixel. Exporting videos from the phone is an absolute pain.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Adventure Time</title>
		<link href="https://capybar.github.io/posts/2020-05-03-Adventure-Time/"/>
		<updated>2020-05-02T20:00:00-04:00</updated>
		<id>https://capybar.github.io/posts/2020-05-03-Adventure-Time/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I love Tumblr, I really do but I think I let the ease of producing stop me from moving forward. The community is fun and I still plan to stick around making themes here or there but it&#39;s finally time to branch out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right now I&#39;m currently writing my posts in &lt;a href=&quot;https://typora.io/&quot;&gt;Typora&lt;/a&gt; in mark down  and man it&#39;s bringing me back to the days of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.latex-project.org/&quot;&gt;LaTeX&lt;/a&gt; which is actually pretty funny because this text editor supports &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mathjax.org/&quot;&gt;MathJax&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Writing is actually fun! I know I post nonsense on Twitter and Tumblr but this blog let&#39;s me post learning nonsense in longform. I am excited to press on with learning front end and actually documenting my experience. The best part? I own the data on this here computer and can write OFF LINE!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Setting Up Eleventy</title>
		<link href="https://capybar.github.io/posts/firstpost/"/>
		<updated>2020-05-03T20:00:00-04:00</updated>
		<id>https://capybar.github.io/posts/firstpost/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m an avid user of Tumblr. I love Tumblr. I love the functionality and how quick it is to make a theme. I love the theme developing community BUT I don&#39;t like the writing experience. It&#39;s good for long notes however what if I want to post crap? And I always want to post crap!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My first foray with Static Site Generators was with Jekyll but I found it difficult to set up. Gems? What and why do I need that? Making a theme for Jekyll is kind of a hassle. Also at the time, Jekyll was not easy to use for a Windows person like me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.11ty.dev/&quot;&gt;llty&lt;/a&gt; is very easy and quick to install. Here&#39;s a guide to how I set it up. This is not the best guide or the best way to do things but ya know, we&#39;re all learning and having fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;pre-install&quot;&gt;Pre-install &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;#pre-install&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before doing anything, stop and &lt;a href=&quot;https://learntocodewith.me/getting-started/topics/command-line/&quot;&gt;learn a bit&lt;/a&gt; about the command line. &lt;a href=&quot;https://git-scm.com/book/en/v2/Getting-Started-Installing-Git&quot;&gt;Install Git&lt;/a&gt; and watch + work out the git tutorial from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=SWYqp7iY_Tc&quot;&gt;Traversy Media&#39;s Youtube video&lt;/a&gt; . I do everything from Microsoft&#39;s Command Line and I don&#39;t use the git command line. Next you&#39;ll want to install NPM using the command line. Follow the instructions &lt;a href=&quot;https://phoenixnap.com/kb/install-node-js-npm-on-windows&quot;&gt;for Windows&lt;/a&gt; very carefully.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was a noob and didn&#39;t know what global versus local meant. Local means in a specific folder so only that folder can use what you install. Global means in some designated place that every folder has access to. If you&#39;re coming from Tumbrl, also know that directory means folder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;install-time!!&quot;&gt;Install Time!! &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;#install-time!!&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you are ever stuck, stop and look up the terms you don&#39;t understand!&lt;/em&gt; You don&#39;t need to know everything. You just need to know enough. I didn&#39;t know what liquid format was or njk and I&#39;m still not sure about JSON. &lt;a href=&quot;https://shopify.github.io/liquid/basics/introduction/&quot;&gt;Liquid template language&lt;/a&gt; is very similar to Tumblr&#39;s {block} structures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Create a folder named &lt;em&gt;blog&lt;/em&gt; . I made this folder in my documents folder but it doesn&#39;t really matter where you make it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now hover over that folder, hold the cmd button and right click. Click &amp;quot;copy path&amp;quot;. Another easier way to get the location of the folder is by dropping the folder in your internet browser and copying it from there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the command line type cd and right click paste the location of your blog. Now type &lt;code&gt;npm --version&lt;/code&gt; to make sure you have npm 8 or higher. NPM by the way stands for Node Package Manager. If you do feel free to continue on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Install 11ty by typing &lt;code&gt;npm install -g @11ty/eleventy&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/11ty/eleventy-base-blog&quot;&gt;Clone the 11ty base blog&lt;/a&gt; by clicking the &amp;quot;clone or download&amp;quot; button at that link. Cloning basically means to copy. What I actually did was individually copied the files and folders one at a time and put them in the blog folder because I didn&#39;t really know how cloning worked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back to the command line you&#39;re  going to need to install a few plugins by copy pasting and pressing enter for these:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;npm install @11ty/eleventy-plugin-rss
npm install @11ty/eleventy-plugin-syntaxhighlight
npm install @11ty/eleventy-navigation
npm install markdown-it
npm install markdown-it-anchor
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In your blog folder, look for a file named .eleventy.js. Open it in any old text editor and paste this in it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; eleventyConfig.addPassthroughCopy(&#39;css&#39;)
  return {
    passthroughFileCopy: true
  }// rest of .eleventy.js config
};
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now back in the command line, type &lt;code&gt;eleventy --serve&lt;/code&gt; this will serve your website. Go to &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:8080/&quot;&gt;http://localhost:8080/&lt;/a&gt; and you should be able to see your site. If not that means something wrong happened. Maybe the instructions I gave were terrible.  In that case &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.filamentgroup.com/lab/build-a-blog/&quot;&gt;go here&lt;/a&gt;. Wish I&#39;d discovered this post earlier. Oh well.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Complexity is Sometimes the Problem</title>
		<link href="https://capybar.github.io/posts/2020-05-09-Free-Code_Camp/"/>
		<updated>2020-05-08T20:00:00-04:00</updated>
		<id>https://capybar.github.io/posts/2020-05-09-Free-Code_Camp/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A few months ago I decided to give &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.freecodecamp.org/&quot;&gt;FreeCodeCamp&lt;/a&gt; (FCC) a go. As of submitting this post, I&#39;m basically done with the Responsive Webdesign Certificate. I already knew the majority of this stuff way before FCC, however I still got a lot out of this, especially the projects. The most valuable lesson and challenge is that of using only what you need.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Tribute page gets bad rep for not requiring much. I saw this as an opportunity to try to use as much newness that I didn&#39;t know about prior to FCC. You really can create an entire web page with almost no &lt;code&gt;div&lt;/code&gt; tags.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My CSS usually balloons to over 800 lines of code but this page? 64! And a huge part of this was because of the semantic HTML. It was easier to see how inheritance works once the divs weren&#39;t mysteries. I opted against using front end frameworks and the tiny bit of javascript that I knew because the purpose of this and all things is not to race ahead but to make the most of what you&#39;re learning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can view all my FCC projects on &lt;a href=&quot;https://codepen.io/smolcodes&quot;&gt;Codepen&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Making CSS Art</title>
		<link href="https://capybar.github.io/posts/2020-05-22-beginnerguide/"/>
		<updated>2020-05-10T20:00:00-04:00</updated>
		<id>https://capybar.github.io/posts/2020-05-22-beginnerguide/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today I made a very simple picture of coffee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;codepen&quot; data-height=&quot;265&quot; data-theme-id=&quot;light&quot; data-default-tab=&quot;css,result&quot; data-user=&quot;smolcodes&quot; data-slug-hash=&quot;rNOKMwM&quot; style=&quot;height: 265px; box-sizing: border-box; display: flex; align-items: center; justify-content: center; border: 2px solid; margin: 1em 0; padding: 1em;&quot; data-pen-title=&quot;coffee&quot;&gt;
  &lt;span&gt;See the Pen &lt;a href=&quot;https://codepen.io/smolcodes/pen/rNOKMwM&quot;&gt;
  coffee&lt;/a&gt; by smolcodes (&lt;a href=&quot;https://codepen.io/smolcodes&quot;&gt;@smolcodes&lt;/a&gt;)
  on &lt;a href=&quot;https://codepen.io/&quot;&gt;CodePen&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://static.codepen.io/assets/embed/ei.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is my first time trying to draw something with CSS. I read &lt;a href=&quot;https://hacks.mozilla.org/2014/09/single-div-drawings-with-css/&quot;&gt;Lynn&#39;s&lt;/a&gt; tutorial but was still a bit confused until I got up and actually started the drawing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to CSS&#39;s :before and :after, one div is actually three and if you cheat a bit, the body is also a div so you have access to 5 divs!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For my first piece I tried initially for a complicated shaded coffee cup but that got overwhelming so I switched to a more simpler drawing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The key to this drawing was being organized. There are two parts to a coffee cup: the cup and the handle. The top saying coffee was just for the lolz. This is the canvas&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;div id=&amp;quot;cup&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now for the styling. It&#39;s good to first create a skeleton&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;#cup:before {
//the title is here
}
#cup {
//this is the cup&#39;s body
}
#cup:after {
//this is the 
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once everything was organized, I created the outline of the cup and handle. The z-index is in the order of :before, #div and :after. Only having one element meant I had to be creative about making the handle. A simple trick was to use inset box shadows. Box shadows don&#39;t stack. They always start from the same beginning position so to create the illusion, I had two layers, the background color for the handle and black for the inner line of the handle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;body {
  background:aquamarine;
  display:flex;
  justify-content:center;
}
#cup:before {
  display:block;
  content:&amp;quot;Coffe&amp;quot;;
  color:coral;
  font-weight:bold;
  font-size:52px;
}
#cup {
  border: 6px solid black;
  width: 180px;
  height:200px; 
  margin-top:10%;
  border-radius:0% 0% 60% 60%;
}
#cup:after {
  display:block;
  content: &amp;quot;&amp;quot;;
  height:70px;
  width:40px;
  margin-left:180px;
  margin-top:60px;
  border:6px solid black;
  border-top-right-radius:30%;
  border-bottom-right-radius:30%;
  box-shadow:inset -4px 4px aquamarine,
             inset 0px -4px aquamarine,
             inset -10px 8px black,
             inset -2px -10px black;
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final step was to add a bit more styles. I used the same inset box trick again to create the coffee in the cup with a bit of foam on top.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;body {
  background:aquamarine;
  display:flex;
  justify-content:center;
}
#cup:before {
  display:block;
  content:&amp;quot;Coffe&amp;quot;;
  color:coral;
  font-weight:bold;
  font-size:52px;
  margin-top:-58%;
  margin-left:55%;
  padding-top:10px;
  padding-right:10px;
  z-index:-6;
  border-top:8px solid coral;
}
#cup {
  border: 6px solid black;
  width: 180px;
  height:200px; 
  margin-top:10%;
  border-radius:0% 0% 60% 60%;
  box-shadow: inset 0px 8px 0px white,
         inset 0px 26px 0px burlywood,
             inset 0px 44px 0px aquamarine,
    inset 0px 48px 0px black,
    inset 0px 82px 0px coral,
    inset 0px 86px 0px black,
           90px -100px white;
  z-index:10;
}
#cup:after {
  display:block;
  content: &amp;quot;&amp;quot;;
  height:70px;
  width:40px;
  margin-left:180px;
  margin-top:60px;
  border:6px solid black;
  border-top-right-radius:30%;
  border-bottom-right-radius:30%;
  box-shadow:inset -4px 4px aquamarine,
             inset 0px -4px aquamarine,
             inset -10px 8px black,
             inset -2px -10px black;
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;​&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Life So Far</title>
		<link href="https://capybar.github.io/posts/2020-05-15-Where/"/>
		<updated>2020-05-14T20:00:00-04:00</updated>
		<id>https://capybar.github.io/posts/2020-05-15-Where/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I haven&#39;t written a pandemic update in a while. These posts -although useless - are pretty cathartic. Starting last week I started to pick up my mood again all though it is always at the cusp of falling. I know why. I find my worrying goes against the consensus. I considered not writing these anymore but I decided to continue 100% because &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kooslooijesteijn.net/journal-newest-first&quot;&gt;Koos&#39; pandemic journal&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This journal is here anyway, because these are tough times to many. We’re more alone than ever. And maybe something I share in here will be useful to you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;koos&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is comforting to know, somewhere in Germany, someone is also going through similar feelings as I.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main driver of why I put things on the internet is so I can remember who I was at any given time. I like to occasionally reach back to something from 10 years ago and see &amp;quot;ah, that&#39;s what I value. My humor sucked then, nice&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I touched on this in an earlier post but part of why I wanted to get into SSGs is to own my content. I&#39;d like Tumblr to stick around but I don&#39;t believe that will be the case. Where will my content go when Tumblr is gone? This current blog is being hosted on &lt;a href=&quot;https://vercel.com/&quot;&gt;Vercel&lt;/a&gt;, however it is possible that it won&#39;t stick around but all these mark down files are in two places: github and my laptop. So the contents of my blog are safe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;connecting&quot;&gt;Connecting &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;#connecting&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During this pandemic, I&#39;ve been keeping in touch with friends, family and coworkers via text and social media. It is not the same. You can&#39;t really emote through tonality. You can&#39;t really be spontaneous either. And Zoom is terrible. Video chatting is alright. The converse is also true. I read people through their voice so without tools of inference, I find we&#39;re all merely present.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-i&#39;ve-been-up-to&quot;&gt;What I&#39;ve been up to &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;#what-i&#39;ve-been-up-to&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reading on the internet&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://themargins.substack.com/archive?sort=new&quot;&gt;The Margins&lt;/a&gt; This newsletter is by far the most interesting one I&#39;ve read in a while.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://quantum.country/&quot;&gt;Quantumn Intro&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://notes.andymatuschak.org/Evergreen_notes&quot;&gt;Evergreen Notes&lt;/a&gt; I think I&#39;ll stick to good ol pen and paper. This sounds a lot like very organized mind mapping&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://martinschneider.me/articles/goodbye-sapper-hello-eleventy/&quot;&gt;A Blog Post about 11ty&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://mxstbr.com/thoughts/css-in-js&quot;&gt;CSS in JS&lt;/a&gt; I am not convinced. Also I&#39;m only 1/4 through Gordon Zhou&#39;s JS course. Yes, I know, I should shove it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learning on the Internet&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.atlassian.com/git/tutorials/syncing/git-push&quot;&gt;Git and Version Control&lt;/a&gt; One day...&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://egghead.io/browse/frameworks/11ty&quot;&gt;Egghead 11ty&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am learning to cook. Here&#39;s the meals thus far. I started cooking three weeks ago&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://capybar.github.io/posts/2020-05-15-Where/%5Bhttps://www.reddit.com/r/Cooking/comments/6y7dkr/recipe_how_to_make_sichuan_dan_dan_noodles_%E6%8B%85%E6%8B%85%E9%9D%A2/%5D(https://www.reddit.com/r/Cooking/comments/6y7dkr/recipe_how_to_make_sichuan_dan_dan_noodles_%E6%8B%85%E6%8B%85%E9%9D%A2/)&quot;&gt;Dan Dan Noodles&lt;/a&gt; My sister made the chili oil-which btw is time consuming. The rest of the meal was easier to do. The sauce is amazing! This is an instant favorite&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6QQ67F8y2b8&amp;amp;t=253s&quot;&gt;Bibimbap&lt;/a&gt; This isn&#39;t hard but it does take a bit of time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=i1djfV9uigc&amp;amp;t=701s&quot;&gt;Japchae&lt;/a&gt; This is a simple noodle dish. It&#39;s a good side but I learned not a good main.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.food.com/recipe/roasted-butternut-squash-red-grapes-and-sage-147381&quot;&gt;Squash with Grapes&lt;/a&gt; It is very easy to make and very delicious&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=bJUiWdM__Qw&quot;&gt;Aglio e Olio&lt;/a&gt; I didn&#39;t use the video I linked to. I used The Cook&#39;s Illustrated Cookbook. I was not a fan of this recipe. The meal wasn&#39;t flavorful enough for me.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.food.com/recipe/best-banana-bread-2886&quot;&gt;Banana Bread&lt;/a&gt; The recipe I used for this also is not the link and is from Cook&#39;s Illustrated.  Add cranberries to make the bread really pop out.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reading and Learning not on the internet&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Played a few new board games
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Evolution: I love this game. I like how interactive it is and also its quirky fun design.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;7 Wonders: it&#39;s a very light Mars. It&#39;s fun and short&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wingspan: It&#39;s beautiful and all the pieces have a nice tactical feel to them, especially the eggs. But the game itself is ok&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go. This is uhh a learning journey. I don&#39;t understand it yet. I&#39;m right now only using the 9x9 board.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Braille. Braille is proving to be quite difficult. I, as a sighted person, don&#39;t cheat and look at the dots btw.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;coffee&quot;&gt;Coffee &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;#coffee&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coffee gets its own section. The first week of the pandemic, I got really into making coffee. Making coffee like any other hobby goes on a scale of  being very affordable to being ... uh, expensive  Luckily most tools you need to make different good cups of coffee are tools you can use for other things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The basics are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A scale. They are about 12$&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A coffee grinder. I bought mine from a grocery store for 20$. It has the essential settings: fine, medium and coarse.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A water heater. These are around 14$-20$. Don&#39;t go too cheap on this though. Some of the very cheap ones have plastic that flakes off on the inside..which is just...weird.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some sort of funnel and some sort of filter. I have before used a sift and paper towels before. The coffee btw while not great was still much better than a corner store&#39;s.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Different coffee equipment I own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Starbucks silicon pourover set: The funnel on top of a mug is great. Don&#39;t use the actual glass container though. It&#39;s too big for the funnel&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chemex. This is the best coffee machine I have ever gotten. The hour glass shape makes a huge difference in trapping in the heat. Don&#39;t make the mistake I made of using a fabric filter. It is better for the environment but impossible to clean. Go for a metal mesh filter.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bedbathandbeyond.com/store/product/bialetti-moka-express-reg-6-cup-model-6800-stovetop-espresso-maker/1010182115?skuId=10182115&amp;amp;mcid=PS_googlepla&quot;&gt;Moka pot&lt;/a&gt; . My goal is to master making moka pot coffee before the pandemic is over. Moka pots are a weird relic of the mid 1900s and apparently they&#39;re still floating all over Italy. My moka pot is pretty old. I think it used to be my grandmother&#39;s? Sure you can buy them online for 15$ but you could probably just as easily and cheaply purchase one from a garage sale. Be warned: moka coffee is somewhere between a shot of espresso and a cup of coffee.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Aeropress I used this once. And I think I might start up using it again.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coffees I&#39;ve made&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dalgona 3 ways:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;With Nestle Instant Coffee: This was by far the easiest decent tasting way&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;With pourover coffee: You need to double the sugar to make up for the lack of instant coffee in order to foam the coffee&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;With moka coffee: This was a complete failure. The problem is it is best done with a hand mixer-not a whisk.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Moka pot coffee: it is a very finicky kind of machine. Using hot water to start is better than cold water. I haven&#39;t figured out how to make it  without a hint of burntness.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To future me: don&#39;t look at this a year from now and think &amp;quot;I&#39;m not in a pandemic and I accomplished so much more when I was&amp;quot;. You had a ton of days where you did nothing but panic stare at your phone. And most days you merely existed. To me four days from now try not to burden yourself with &amp;quot;making the most of it and being productive AF&amp;quot;.You know this post is a summary of the past two months. You know you didn&#39;t do that much but maybe that&#39;s okay.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
</feed>